<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Willy Barro]]></title>
  <link href="http://willybarro.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://willybarro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-15T21:32:36-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://willybarro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Willy Barro]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once upon a time...]]></title>
    <link href="http://willybarro.github.io/blog/2013/08/15/once-upon-a-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-15T19:13:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://willybarro.github.io/blog/2013/08/15/once-upon-a-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>… there was a guy on his early 20s, he was a software developer who wondered to write on his own blog. He was amazed by how marvelous would his world be if he could express himself, his coding experiences, self-rants, tutorials, puzzles, talk about conferences he attended, about every-day coding challenges and general hackish or nerdish stuff.</p>

<p>His friends told him to write a blog, his old bosses told him to write a blog, even his girlfriend told him to write a blog. And he almost got there in <strong>X</strong> different times, with dozens of completely different themes, in <strong>Y</strong> different CMS&rsquo;s (Wordpress, Jekyll, home baked…) and in <strong>Z</strong> completely different attempts on a couple of years of this new millenium.</p>

<p>You know in all those blogging-attempts what he ~really~ accomplished? <strong><a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/1.4.2/docs/api/java/lang/NullPointerException.html">Absolutely Nothing</a>!</strong></p>

<p>And why was that? Why this godamned developer couldn&rsquo;t publish his own blog? Was that a technical problem? Was that a world-class problem? Was every server in the world down?</p>

<p><strong>Hell no!</strong> It&rsquo;s just his indecisions on selecting a beautiful theme for his own fucking blog. And he&rsquo;s not even a designer, ux designer or average hipster. He&rsquo;s a fucking <strong>developer</strong>!</p>

<h2>Back to reality</h2>

<p>Based on our little tale above, let me tell you something:</p>

<blockquote><p>Forget about that damn theme and &ldquo;WRITE, MOTHER FUCKER!&rdquo; <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p></blockquote>

<p>If your content is good, nobody will really care if you have a not-so-beautiful theme, and in case you just don&rsquo;t get the hang of blog writing, you would have just spent your time making your blog shine beautifully with no reason at all. So <em>&ldquo;WRITE, MOTHER FUCKER!&rdquo;</em>.</p>

<p>Leave all those problems to the future. I guarantee that you&rsquo;ll bump on a cool theme in no time or maybe you&rsquo;ll just forget it.</p>

<p>Not convinced yet? Look at any online <a href="http://www.php.net/manual/">language</a> <a href="http://www.python.org/doc/">documentation</a>, these docs doesn&rsquo;t look really sexy right? If those guys were not following the <em>&ldquo;WRITE, MOTHER FUCKER&rdquo;</em> line of thought, we would need to scrap infinite sourcefiles just to know what that nasty &ldquo;<a href="http://www.php.net/manual/en/function.strpbrk.php">str_pbrk</a>&rdquo; function does.</p>

<p>So, stop crying like a baby and &ldquo;WRITE, MOTHER FUCKER!&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>Finally</h2>

<p>I hope this will help someone to get the courage to publish their blogs and stop procrastinating behind that damned wall of &ldquo;it&rsquo;s not ready yet&rdquo; or &ldquo;it&rsquo;s ugly, people won&rsquo;t like it&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>Just a little more&hellip;</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve bumped up coincidentally (or not) into a great Octopress theme when I decided to follow my <em>&ldquo;WRITE, MOTHER FUCKER!&rdquo;</em> not-so <em>manifesto</em>. All credits to <a href="http://shashankmehta.in/archive/2012/greyshade.html">Shashank Mehta</a>.</p>

<p>Oh… and, as you may already know, my native language is not english, so, please ignore any english mistakes or if you have a great soul, send me a fix on <a href="http://www.twitter.com/willybarro">twitter @willybarro</a>.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Borrowed from the fun &ldquo;Programming Motherfucker&rdquo; manifesto &ndash; <a href="http://programming-motherfucker.com/">http://programming-motherfucker.com/</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
